

Summary:

I'm Software Engineer with more than 9 years experience in all phases of software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design and software testing.

I would like to work in an environment that provides opportunities for professional development, and enables to learn more about dealing with difficult and critical situations.

Personal information:

Name Emad Mohammed Mohammed Ali

Military status finished

Mobile number 01223872695

Address Dokki - Giza

Email eng.emadmohamedphp@gmail.com

Linkedin https://eq.linkedin.com/in/emad-mohamed-b7a1a262

wuzzuf http://wuzzuf.net/me/emadmohamedali

Github https://github.com/EmadMohDev

current position PHP Teamlead

Experience period 9 years

Skype emad.mohamed_edigits

Education:

University: Faculty of Engineering in Shubra - Banha University 2009

department: computer Science

Graduation degree: very good

Project degree : Excellent

Technologies

- Html, Html5
- Css, Css3
- Java script
- jQuery
- jQuery Ui
- jQueryMobile
- AJAX
- JSON
- Google Maps
- bootstrap3
- Experience with PHP
- Experience with MYSQL
- Good knowledge of version control tools like GIT
- Excellent knowledge of OOP basics.
- Good knowledge of MVC.
- Experience with XML
- Experience with RSS
- Experience with native php
- Experience with "YII" framework.
- Experience with "Cakephp" framework.
- Experience with "laravel" framework .
- Experience with "codeignitor" framework .
- familiar with Sass.
- familiar with angular is.
- familiar with Node js.
- familiar with MongoDB.
- familiar with CMS like wordpress.
- familiar with ionic framework (mobile cross platform).
- familiar with phoneGap framework (mobile cross platform).
- Experience in common third-party APIs (google, facebook, twitter,paypal, etc).
- Experience with RESTful / SOAP Web Services.
- familiar with linux (ubuntu).
- familiar with java
- familiar with Vue Js
- familiar with React Js
- graphQl

Work Experience:

> Ivas

link: http://www.ivas.mobi/

Title: Team Lead (1/2018 until Now)

My roles & responsibilities :

- Lead the Development team.
- Review code to make sure that matching best practices, name convention and make all merging on gitlab.
- Support team in complicated tasks
- Make a deep and full testing for all new projects
- Good background in Linux development and administration.
- Sending regular updates about projects status
- Building reusable code and libraries for future use
- Handle recruitment

Title: senior Software Engineer (1/2016 until 12/2017)

• My roles & responsibilities :

- -Participates in all phases of software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design and software testing.
- -work on "VAS" value added service for mobile apps like call tones "rbts" and web push contents.
- Designs and develops relational database systems and their web interfaces.
- Provide written status reports & documentation internally & for end users.
- Produce detailed specifications.
- Drawing up test strategies, stories, and test cases to test applications.
- Resolve technical issues through debugging, research and investigation.
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the core product software and databases to ensure strong optimization and functionality.
- Follow industry best practices.
- Develop and deploy new features to facilitate related procedures and tools if necessary.
- Ensure the quality of the developed applications.
- Developing applications using laravel framework.
- maintain and fix problems for old projects.

Sada Code

link: https://sadacode.com/

Title: senior php Developer (1/2015 until 12/2015)

My roles & responsibilities :

- -Drawing up test strategies, stories, and test cases to test applications.
- -Testing applications for quality assurance.
- -Deployment, maintenance and evolution of systems and applications.
- Resolve technical issues through debugging, research and investigation.
- -Analysis problems and design best solutions utilizing the technical skills of the team.
- -Read the requirements of the project and understand it then make analysis for it.
- -Discuss my analysis with my team.
- -distribution the tasks to my team.
- -Follow my team and discussing the tasks entrusted to them, and assemble the final work.
- Developing web applications using CakePHP framework.

Egprosolution

link: http://www.ukprosolutions.com/

Title: work as junior php Developer (1/2013 to 12/2014)

- Description:
- Developing web applications using Yii framework.
- Developing web applications using Codeignitor framework.

Soft Skills:

- smart thinking.
- self-motivated.
- Ambitious.
- problem solving skills.
- business analysis skills.
- Strong communication and interpersonal skills.
- Interactive and fast enough to learn new technologies.
- Ability to work in a group or individually according to job requirements.

Languages:

- Arabic : Native language.

- English: very good read/write/speak.

Projects

graphQl Demo

https://github.com/EmadMohDev/graphql-laravel

Project description:

This is demo to use graphQl technology with Laravel9 Here we make list for users, departments Also we make mutations for department CRUD Also we make filter by arguments by make queries

√Technologies: PHP8 & Laravel9 & graphQI

> Aghezty

https://aghezty.com/

Jan 2020 - May 2020

Project description

Ecommerce website that user can register and login by his account

Then make order by 3 available types (cash / Visa nbe / Visa CIB)

and It contains a wonderful filter through which you can search by price range , brand filter , category filter

and there is a dashboard to complete control all items on the website

✓Technologies: PHP7&Laravel & bootstrap 4 & SASS & Checkout is integration for CIB and NBE

> Islamic portal for MBC

May 2020 – Jun 2020

Project description

It's Islamic portal that consist of many Sheikhs.

Also there is muslim guide like: zakaa / mirtah calculate / praytimes / Electronic rosary / Neatest

Mosque

✓Technologies : PHP7&Laravel & bootstrap 4 & SASS & Soap api & WSDL

Whatsappy

Jan 2020 – Mar 2020

Project description

Entertainment web app that enable user to download or share media to the whatsapp app also enable user to write on images then share it to the whatsapp.

✓Technologies : PHP7&Laravel & bootstrap 4 & SASS &Restful api & Graph QL

> Greetings

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

Project description

Entertainment web app that enable user to:

- 1- Cut the video
- 2- Cut the audio
- 3- Merge an image and audio to generate a video
- 4- Merge multiple image to generate a vide
- 5- Make animation on the generated video
- 6- Write on the image
- 7- Write on the video
- 8- Make water marke on the video

√Technologies: php7&Laravel & Vue js & bootstrap 4 &FFMPEG

> SMS Dashboard :

A dashboard that control to send bulk SMS to kannel

Technologies: php7 & kannel